<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on HAL Management Console</title><link>https://hal.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in Home on HAL Management Console</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://hal.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Build &amp; Run</title><link>https://hal.github.io/development/build-run/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 16:29:52 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://hal.github.io/development/build-run/</guid><description>This page explains how to build, run and debug the console. We recommend to use Maven and the command line. This will work reliably across different environments and IDEs. To get a better understanding of the build process, we recommend that you take a look at the architecture as well.
All recent development happens in the branch main. There are additional branches mainly used for maintenance.
Build If not already done, clone the code from https://github.</description></item><item><title>Get Started</title><link>https://hal.github.io/documentation/get-started/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 16:28:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://hal.github.io/documentation/get-started/</guid><description>The HAL management console is part of every WildFly and JBoss EAP installation. To get started simply fire up your browser and open http://localhost:9990.
Standalone Mode Besides that you can run the console on its own aka standalone mode. HAL is a RIA with no server side dependencies. When run on its own, HAL will show a dialog when it&amp;rsquo;s started. You have to provide the URL of the management endpoint you want to connect to.</description></item><item><title>Architecture</title><link>https://hal.github.io/development/architecture/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 16:30:01 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://hal.github.io/development/architecture/</guid><description>HAL is a client side RIA without server side dependencies. It is a GWT application - which means it&amp;rsquo;s written almost completely in Java. GWT is used to transpile the Java code into a bunch of JavaScript, HTML and CSS files. HAL also uses external JavaScript dependencies. These dependencies are managed using NPM and bundled using Parcel. NPM and Parcel are integrated into the Maven build using the maven-frontend-plugin.
We use the model view presenter pattern and GWTP for its implementation.</description></item><item><title>Basic Concepts</title><link>https://hal.github.io/documentation/concepts/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 16:29:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://hal.github.io/documentation/concepts/</guid><description>HAL uses a set of UI components which follow the design guides from PatternFly. If necessary, these UI components are extended and adapted to the needs of HAL. The following chapters explain the most important concepts and their use.
Header &amp;amp; Footer The header and footer provide access to global features and give feedback about various states of WildFly. The color of the top line in the header shows the used theme:</description></item><item><title>Building Blocks</title><link>https://hal.github.io/development/building-blocks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 16:30:11 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://hal.github.io/development/building-blocks/</guid><description>This section describes the main building blocks and central concepts in HAL. The chapters follow a logical order starting from the fundamental concepts to the higher-level modules.
Dependency Injection HAL uses GIN for dependency injection. Although no longer actively developed, GIN is a stable and mature DI framework. In the long run we want to replace GIN with Dagger. But this requires a new GWTP version which currently depends on GIN.</description></item><item><title>Manual</title><link>https://hal.github.io/documentation/manual/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 16:29:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://hal.github.io/documentation/manual/</guid><description>The HAL management console features a rich user interface to configure, analyse and monitor the complete WildFly management model. The console uses six top level categories: homepage, deployments, configuration, runtime, patching and access control. In addition HAL uses a header and footer to provide access to global features and give feedback about various states of WildFly and HAL.
This page gives a quick introduction to the main elements in the header and footer and the six top level categories.</description></item><item><title>Branches</title><link>https://hal.github.io/development/branches/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 16:29:52 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://hal.github.io/development/branches/</guid><description>This page lists the branches of HAL and describes their relation to the WildFly and EAP major versions. If you want to see a full list of all HAL releases and a detailed changelog, please go to the release notes.
The information on this page is important if you want to contribute to HAL. Especially if you like to backport an issue or want to submit a PR for maintenance.</description></item><item><title>Keycloak SSO</title><link>https://hal.github.io/documentation/howto/keycloak-sso/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 11:29:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://hal.github.io/documentation/howto/keycloak-sso/</guid><description>When user configures Wildfly to authenticate user to Keycloak SSO, HAL supports the authentication the following way:
HAL redirects the login attempt to keycloak server, if successful redirect back to HAL. Provide the logout option in HAL to call the logout page on keycloak. This is displayed under the username in the header section. Displays basic Keycloak settings in the Access Control page. Displays a link to user profile on Keycloak server.</description></item><item><title>Contribute</title><link>https://hal.github.io/documentation/contribute/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 16:30:37 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://hal.github.io/documentation/contribute/</guid><description>First off, thank you for considering contributing to HAL. It&amp;rsquo;s people like you that make HAL such a great tool. HAL is an open source project and we love to receive contributions from our community — you! There are many ways to contribute, from writing tutorials or blog posts, improving the documentation, submitting bug reports and feature requests or writing code which can be incorporated into HAL itself.
Getting involved is easier than you think.</description></item><item><title>Roadmap</title><link>https://hal.github.io/documentation/roadmap/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 11:24:57 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://hal.github.io/documentation/roadmap/</guid><description>HAL is community-driven and as such the roadmap constantly evolves to reflect the users needs and contributions. You can find a list of planned issues and feature requests in our issue tracker.
For more details take a look at the list of bugs, enhancements and feature requests. We&amp;rsquo;re always happy for you to step in and contribute in any way.
Long-Term Beyond that we&amp;rsquo;ve identified some major enhancements and topics we&amp;rsquo;d like to work on:</description></item><item><title>2.0.6.Final</title><link>https://hal.github.io/releases/2.0.6.final/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2018 18:35:30 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://hal.github.io/releases/2.0.6.final/</guid><description>Target: EAP 6.2.0 Release Stream: 2.0.6.Final Core Console: 2.0.6.Final Tracking Issue: BZ1024560 Release Notes HAL-285: Syslog handler is missing in setting of Handlers in Management Console HAL-284: Changing scope type of the role leads to &amp;ldquo;Failed to save&amp;rdquo; error HAL-281: Unclear error message when trying to configure Auditor role as Administrator HAL-280: Unable to List Driver during Datasource Creation via the management console HAL-278: List attributes in &amp;ldquo;need help&amp;rdquo; in same order as in settings tabs HAL-275: Improve error handling when operating on stopped server instances HAL-274: RunAs after switching roles results in an error HAL-264: Resource adapter inline editing problems HAL-263: Modal windows are sized inconsistently HAL-261: Role management mapping should be accessible for Auditor HAL-256: Module and ClassName fields are disabled in new Custom handler dialog HAL-255: Runtime name input disable in new Unmanaged Deployment dialog HAL-253: Domain mode: kill an unresponsive JVM HAL-250: Revert project name references HAL-244: Unable to unset &amp;ldquo;Default From&amp;rdquo; attribute in Mail Session administration HAL-241: Role names seem to be case insensitive but roles tab of the console assumes they are ALLCAPS HAL-240: Push translations to translate.</description></item><item><title>2.1.1.Final</title><link>https://hal.github.io/releases/2.1.1.final/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2018 18:34:56 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://hal.github.io/releases/2.1.1.final/</guid><description>Target: WildFly 8.0.0.Final Release Stream: 2.1.1.Final Core Console: 2.1.1.Final Tracking Issue: WFLY-2827 New &amp;amp; Improved Features Topology View Performance RBAC sensitive UI Bugfixes HAL-337: Partly undo fix which was introduced by HAL-10 HAL-336: Show a warning and change default place to &amp;ldquo;Profiles&amp;rdquo; if there are no groups defined. HAL-335: Workaround using include-aliases=true; more fail-safe RBACGatekeeper HAL-331: Add horizontal scrolling to value table in properties table HAL-329: Fix top level navigation for MBUI dialogs HAL-328: Navigation not highlighted for MBUI dialogs HAL-327: Add RBAC check for server reload button HAL-326: remote repo in dev mode HAL-321: properly clear and reset dialog state upon removal of resources HAL-320: Progress bar for RBAC related r-r-d HAL-319: Scope assignment and statement context resolution HAL-317: Undefine attribute doesn&amp;rsquo;t work HAL-315: &amp;ldquo;Max Retry&amp;rdquo; -&amp;gt; &amp;ldquo;Max Retry Interval&amp;rdquo; HAL-313: Async handlers don&amp;rsquo;t provide handlers to subviews - ie no nesting allowed!</description></item><item><title>2.2.6.Final</title><link>https://hal.github.io/releases/2.2.6.final/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2018 18:33:59 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://hal.github.io/releases/2.2.6.final/</guid><description>Target: WildFly 8.1.0.Final Release Stream: 2.2.6.Final Core Console: 2.2.6.Final Tracking Issue: WFLY-3332 New &amp;amp; Improved Features Patching New top level navigation Home page Bugfixes HAL-403: Fix index setup HAL-402: Fix refresh when using view framework HAL-385: Scrollbar for profile selector HAL-384: Only servers which belong to the current profile are part of the verify operation HAL-383: Homepage links don&amp;rsquo;t work as expected HAL-382: Prevent loading of google vis in web mode HAL-381: Default build for community includes modern browsers and en.</description></item><item><title>2.2.8.Final</title><link>https://hal.github.io/releases/2.2.8.final/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2018 18:32:53 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://hal.github.io/releases/2.2.8.final/</guid><description>Target: EAP 6.3.0 Release Stream: 2.2.8.Final Core Console: 2.2.8.Final Tracking Issue: BZ1104216 New &amp;amp; Improved Features Role based access control (RBAC) Patching New top level navigation Home page Bugfixes BZ901227: Allow -1 as default value for modcluster timeout attributes BZ1092650: Add pager to list of EE modules BZ1088314: Fix refresh in JacORB view BZ1081990: Add restart button; fix for one-off patches BZ1081570: Add check if running in domain mode BZ1081186: Change label and help text for GA BZ1080767: Home page string suggestions and corrections BZ1075720: Get rid of patch confirm step BZ1075264: Remove inline warning icon BZ1075169: Fix wizard title BZ1075137: Disable rollback button when no items are available BZ1074675: Modal patch wizard BZ1074623: Fix parsing error BZ1073988: Fix intro paragraph for homepage BZ1073597: Home page task containers show (empty) scrollbar.</description></item><item><title>2.4.9.Final</title><link>https://hal.github.io/releases/2.4.9.final/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2018 18:32:11 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://hal.github.io/releases/2.4.9.final/</guid><description>Target: WildFly 8.2.0.Final WildFly 8.2.1.Final Release Stream: 2.4.9.Final Core Console: 2.4.9.Final Tracking Issue: WFLY-4107 New &amp;amp; Improved Features Updated look &amp;amp; feel. Now follows the Patternfly styles. Improved information architecture: Domain management, deployments and runtime views have been relocated / consolidated Extended / complete subsystem configuration: EE, Undertow, Messaging, IO and Batch Updated model browser: supports inline editing of resources Log Viewer: Tail log files from within the console Picketlink extension: The GUI now ships the picketlink management parts (enabled on demand) Improved runtime monitoring: The charts and data tables have been cleaned up Bugfixes HAL-514: Prepare double click handler on log file table HAL-512: Display deployment &amp;ldquo;status&amp;rdquo; attribute on deployment list HAL-508: Tools links leave wrong name token HAL-507: Tab titles are no longer truncated by default HAL-506: Add operation adresses to tool buttons in logviewer HAL-503: Product and server name are displayed in the browser&amp;rsquo;s title HAL-501: relative-to for file based log handler is only required if path is relative HAL-500: Navigation for RH Access HAL-497: Entire layout of csp plugin falls apart after visiting different page HAL-495: Fix tooltips in topology view HAL-493: Apply patch wizard stuck on patch application step HAL-492: Fix URL fragment problem HAL-490: Distinguish community and product version HAL-487: Fix handler reference bug which was introduced by HAL-313 HAL-486: Invalid default value for &amp;ldquo;Default Module&amp;rdquo; attribute of Virtual Server HAL-484: Resource adapter names not visible HAL-483: Switch back to &amp;lsquo;StandaloneDriverStrategy&amp;rsquo; for standalpone mode HAL-482: Application constraints for logging subsystem HAL-481: Cache Containers doesn&amp;rsquo;t refresh after save HAL-477: Exclude attribute &amp;lsquo;thread-factory&amp;rsquo; from &amp;lsquo;ThreadPoolsView&amp;rsquo; HAL-476: Update to CSP Plugin 0.</description></item><item><title>2.5.5.Final</title><link>https://hal.github.io/releases/2.5.5.final/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2018 18:31:14 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://hal.github.io/releases/2.5.5.final/</guid><description> Target: EAP 6.4.0 Release Stream: 2.5.5.Final Core Console: 2.5.5.Final Tracking Issue: BZ1193523 Bugfixes BZ901260: Updated translations BZ1176249: Product logo depends on product name. BZ1174732: Use &amp;lsquo;{selected.profile}&amp;rsquo; when saving model driven widgets in web presenter BZ1173031: Fix loading settings BZ1172168: Fix match between subsystem key and related subsystem token BZ1170538: Fix in viewframework BZ1167673: Fix search in concurrently opened log files BZ1167525: Fix add mail server dialog BZ1167362: Fix hanging &amp;ldquo;download in progress&amp;rdquo; dialog BZ1166749 / BZ1166737: Visual adjustments for the homepage and the search BZ1159771: Wrong error message in New Connector wizard BZ1026823: run as dialog BZ1017655: Fix validation in WebServicePresenter#onSaveProvider BZ1017059: After :server-set-restart-required operation web console shows reload required message</description></item><item><title>2.7.4.Final</title><link>https://hal.github.io/releases/2.7.4.final/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2018 18:30:25 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://hal.github.io/releases/2.7.4.final/</guid><description>Target: WildFly 9.0.0.Final WildFly 9.0.1.Final Release Stream: 2.7.4.Final Core Console: 2.7.4.Final Tracking Issue: WFLY-4809 New &amp;amp; Improved Features New finder based user interface Replaced JacORB with IIOP OpenJDK subsystem Remoting subsystem Support for datasource templates. Provide all flush-* operations for connection pools Improved log viewer Enhanced model browser with support for singleton resources Get more details about applied patches Ability to launch the management console independently from WildFly Bugfixes HAL-701: Fix broken links on homepage HAL-700: Scrolling with nested presenters HAL-699: Closing of notification messages HAL-698: Reload standalone server, server and groups in domain HAL-697: Scrolling in standalone mode HAL-690, HAL-691: Check and add missing subresource; reset finder column selection HAL-678: Server config settings don&amp;rsquo;t refresh after changes HAL-674: Server groups settings don&amp;rsquo;t refresh after changes HAL-672: Replace old access control UI with finder based UI HAL-665: Replace EJB subsystem with MBUI views HAL-655: Add support for remaining servlet container settings (undertow) HAL-644: Hornetq messaging finder contributions HAL-643: Infinispan cache container become finder contributions HAL-641: Deployment Finder HAL-635: Runtime/Transaction typo fix.</description></item><item><title>2.8.13.Final</title><link>https://hal.github.io/releases/2.8.13.final/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2018 18:29:41 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://hal.github.io/releases/2.8.13.final/</guid><description> Target: WildFly 9.0.2.Final Release Stream: 2.8.13.Final Core Console: 2.8.13.Final Tracking Issue: WFLY-5587</description></item><item><title>2.8.19.Final</title><link>https://hal.github.io/releases/2.8.19.final/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2018 18:29:41 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://hal.github.io/releases/2.8.19.final/</guid><description>Target: WildFly 10.0.0.Final Release Stream: 2.8.19.Final Core Console: 2.8.19.Final Tracking Issue: WFLY-6065 New &amp;amp; Improved Features New homepage Support for suspend and graceful shutdown Replaced HornetQ with ActiveMQ Artemis Request Controller subsystem Deployment Scanner subsystem Bugfixes HAL-1039: Move test connection button to its own page HAL-1034: Add logo image for new product name HAL-1031: Fix confirmation messages in TX log view HAL-1017: JMSMetricPresenter always uses &amp;ldquo;default&amp;rdquo; as part of operation address even if name is changed.</description></item><item><title>2.8.24.Final</title><link>https://hal.github.io/releases/2.8.24.final/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2018 18:27:53 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://hal.github.io/releases/2.8.24.final/</guid><description>Target: EAP 7.0.0 Release Stream: 2.8.24.Final Core Console: 2.8.24.Final Tracking Issue: JBEAP-4088 New &amp;amp; Improved Features New homepage Support for suspend and graceful shutdown Replaced HornetQ with ActiveMQ Artemis Request Controller subsystem Deployment Scanner subsystem Bugfixes JBEAP-3607: Disable filtering before changing column&amp;rsquo;s data JBEAP-3338: Add filter to subsystem column JBEAP-3334: Add product name to window title JBEAP-3150: In Runtime rename HTTP subsystem to Undertow subsystem JBEAP-3150: In Runtime rename HTTP subsystem to Undertow subsystem JBEAP-3084: Unassigning of content from server group shoud be confirmed by clicking &amp;lsquo;Unassign&amp;rsquo; not &amp;lsquo;Assign&amp;rsquo; button JBEAP-3032: Add &amp;lsquo;relative-to&amp;rsquo; attribute in add deployment scanner dialog JBEAP-3001: Missing resource description in &amp;ldquo;Need Help?</description></item><item><title>2.8.27.Final</title><link>https://hal.github.io/releases/2.8.27.final/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2018 22:47:57 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://hal.github.io/releases/2.8.27.final/</guid><description>Target: WildFly 10.1.0.Final Release Stream: 2.8.27.Final Core Console: 2.8.27.Final Tracking Issue: WFLY-6896 Bugfixes HAL-1194: It is not possible to add SAML handler with class name defined HAL-1137: Impossible to read/configure messaging provider journal directory path HAL-1132: Buttons at the end of modal panels get cut off HAL-1111: Web/HTTP - Undertow connectors metrics doesn&amp;rsquo;t work in domain HAL-1107: Non-functioning Korean localization option in web console HAL-1106: Typo in heading of step 1/4 of Create XA Datasource wizard HAL-1102: Web Console - Messaging - Broadcast should allow to add optional field if there is other required field other than Name HAL-1099: Rename Connections to Cluster Connections in Messaging Clustering HAL-1098: Update url in template for MS SQLServer datasource.</description></item><item><title>2.9.15.Final</title><link>https://hal.github.io/releases/2.9.15.final/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2018 22:48:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://hal.github.io/releases/2.9.15.final/</guid><description>Target: WildFly 11.0.0.Final WildFly 12.0.0.Final 7.1.0 Release Stream: 2.9.15.Final Core Console: 2.9.15.Final Tracking Issue: WFLY-9441 Bugfixes HAL HAL-1383: Redesign Elytron policy handling HAL-1378: Add support for match-all attribute on simple-permission-mapper elytron subsystem HAL-1372: Not possible to edit Undertow HTTPS listener without SSL context specified HAL-1365: Not possible to add Elytron policy resource using web console HAL-1363: Add new log elytron resources HAL-1360: Implement missing elytron resources HAL-1358: Duplicite suggested resources in EJB 3 subsystem form in Web Console HAL-1357: Disable nested tables add/remove buttons if there are no table items HAL-1356: Add a button to disable SSO on app security domain in Undertow subsys HAL-1355: Remote address in not shown in configuration changes table in Web Console HAL-1354: Not possible to add permissions of permission-mappings of Elytron simple-permission-mapper HAL-1353: Not possible to view permissions of permission-mappings of Elytron simple-permission-mapper HAL-1352: It is not possible to match rule in authentication context configuration in Web Console HAL-1351: Datasource in Management model cannot be saved HAL-1350: Add support to reset form values for complex attributes HAL-1342: Not possible to create Elytron regex-principal-transformer in web console HAL-1338: Wrong providers tab of Elytron provider loader configuration HAL-1337: Not possible to create Elytron aggregate-principal-transformer or chained-principal-transformer HAL-1336: Links to download deployment content download whole deployment instead of single files HAL-1335: Do not pre-select server-group when assigning a deployment in domain mode HAL-1332: Make browse content available archived deployments HAL-1331: HTTP remote connector is not present in resource table after adding it in Web Console HAL-1330: Not possible to see and edit Elytron trust manager certificate-revocation-list HAL-1325: It is not possible to set -1 to reconnect attempts attribute of messaging bridge HAL-1322: Enables &amp;ldquo;alternatives&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;requires&amp;rdquo; validator by default for ModelNodeFormBuilder HAL-1320: tls attribute is not saved when form is saved HAL-1319: Clarify &amp;lsquo;Reload server(s) now&amp;rsquo; button HAL-1317: attributes supplied with empty string instead of undefined HAL-1316: Not possible to edit New Item Template of Elytron LDAP Key Store HAL-1315: Mandatory &amp;lsquo;enabling&amp;rsquo; checkbox when adding Elytron Configurable HTTP Server Mechanism filter does not work HAL-1314: Outdated link to EAP documentation HAL-1313: Bad style in subsystem configuration tab header HAL-1307: Broadcast/Discovery group is possible to create with just a name HAL-1306: Help section of JGroups &amp;ldquo;add&amp;rdquo; dialog doesn&amp;rsquo;t work HAL-1301: host is not set when browsing via server-groups HAL-1300: Add alternatives validator for credential-reference HAL-1297: Hide XA related attributes for non-XA datasource statistrics HAL-1296: Validate credential-reference attribute value on client side in Web Console HAL-1294: Fix elytron attributes on datasources and resource-adapters HAL-1293: Major and minor versions in datasource wizard are unnecessary HAL-1291: elytron security domain configuration in EJB subsystem HAL-1290: Not possible to view, add or remove Elytron Credential Store aliases HAL-1288: Develop view functionality for application security domain on undertow subsystem HAL-1286: Neither suggestion nor drop-down list for default realm is present when creating security domain HAL-1285: Not possible to create Elytron Credetial Store without all optional attributes of capability-reference specified HAL-1284: It is not possible to add new datasource in Web Console HAL-1282: Web console RBAC Users/Groups descriptions are confusing HAL-1277: Update HAL forms with wildfly domain model HAL-1271: fix handling of groups-properties HAL-1266: Implement attributes changes in wildfly domain model HAL-1265: Not possible to create Elytron custom credetial security factory in standalone mode HAL-1264: Show defaul value for version-comparison attribute in mechanism-provider-filtering-sasl-server-factory view HAL-1262: add socket binding suggestion box to jgroups view HAL-1261: Add button to refresh the prepared transactions statistics for messaging HAL-1260: Add button to refresh the pool statistics for datasources HAL-1259: Add elytron authentication-* resources to HAL HAL-1258: Enhancements to Path configuration in Web Console HAL-1257: Datasource remains saved in Web Console if user closes wizard after test connection is performed HAL-1255: Configuration of singleton policy in singleton subsystem dissapears in Web Console HAL-1254: Support for EAP 7.</description></item><item><title>3.0.0.Final</title><link>https://hal.github.io/releases/3.0.0.final/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 16:43:15 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://hal.github.io/releases/3.0.0.final/</guid><description>Target: WildFly 13.0.0.Final Tag: 3.0.0.Final Tracking Issue: WFLY-10375 New &amp;amp; Improved Features General Place management for finder and applications. Each finder selection and each application has its own distinct URL Cross-links between different parts of HAL (configuration ⟷ runtime ⟷ deployment) Applications / finder selections can be bookmarked Enhanced model browser (visualize deprecated attributes) Macro recording PatternFly compliance Enhanced form items lists properties booleans (w/ expression support) combo boxes with auto complete support JavaScript API Support for (dynamic) extensions written in JavaScript Second level cache for metadata (based on IndexDB and web workers) Finder Navigation using cursor keys.</description></item><item><title>3.0.10.Final</title><link>https://hal.github.io/releases/3.0.10.final/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 08:20:15 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://hal.github.io/releases/3.0.10.final/</guid><description> Target: JBoss EAP 7.2.0 Tag: 3.0.7.Final Tracking Issue: JBEAP-15666 Bugfixes JBEAP-15637 Enable deployments by default JBEAP-15638 Required field error when rolling back a patch JBEAP-15641 The &amp;ldquo;name&amp;rdquo; field of &amp;ldquo;Add&amp;rdquo; dialog for JCA distributed work manager is read only JBEAP-15642 Undeploy operation wording is not unified EAP7-1112 Take a tour wizard is not yet implemented in HAL 3</description></item><item><title>3.0.6.Final</title><link>https://hal.github.io/releases/3.0.6.final/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 16:20:15 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://hal.github.io/releases/3.0.6.final/</guid><description> Target: WildFly 14.0.0.Final WildFly 14.0.1.Final WildFly 15.0.0.Final WildFly 15.0.1.Final Tag: 3.0.6.Final Tracking Issue: WFLY-10955 Bugfixes HAL-1514: Add messaging server requires the path=* subresources if a server already exists HAL-1512: Support Wildfly in EMBEDDED mode HAL-1511: Cross-site scripting (XSS) in JBoss Management Console HAL-1498: Add new elytron resources: certificate-authority-account, custom-security-event-listener, mapped-role-mapper HAL-1496: Add support for ModelType.DOUBLE HAL-1493: Add multi-server support to mod_cluster HAL-1491: Create Empty Deployment dialog is missing close or cancel buttons HAL-1486: Missing replace operation for deployment HAL-1484: HAL does not work in IE11 HAL-1482: Broken CSS for steps in wizard header HAL-1481: Provide datasource properties as suggestions HAL-1479: Unable to cancel forms for Servlet Container / Mime Mapping &amp;amp; Welcome File HAL-1478: Migrate from Bower to Yarn HAL-1474: Support Eclipse MicroProfile Config in Web Console HAL-1472: Cannot enter specific characters in XA properties values HAL-1471: Support for authentication in Keycloak SSO HAL-1470: add-identity in filesystem-realm with no notification HAL-1469: Unable to read or edit categories in logging profile HAL-1468: Implement new infinispan resource: remote-cache-container HAL-1466: Implement new infinispan resources HAL-1465: Implement new elytron resource permission-set HAL-1411: Change &amp;ldquo;Endpoint Configuration&amp;rdquo; view for remoting subsystem HAL-1410: Implement runtime view for Elytron HAL-1407: Add support for configuration changes per server in domain mode HAL-756: Add datasource connection properties- HAL-1392: Session operations for deployments</description></item><item><title>3.1.2.Final</title><link>https://hal.github.io/releases/3.1.2.final/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 15:50:15 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://hal.github.io/releases/3.1.2.final/</guid><description>Target: WildFly 16.0.0.Final Tag: 3.1.2.Final Tracking Issue: WFLY-11408 Bugfixes HAL-1565 Properties form item does not allow square brackets in values HAL-1564 Remove &amp;ldquo;Management Operations&amp;rdquo; item in monitor column in domain mode HAL-1561 Disable &amp;ldquo;View&amp;rdquo; action if messaging server is not started or is inactive. HAL-1560 Add confirmation dialog for messaging server / force failover HAL-1557 Show active management operation from hosts and servers in a central place HAL-1554 Support runtime operations for messaging servers HAL-1552 Macro recording does not work HAL-1551 Set the smallrye subtitle for microprofile-health columns HAL-1550 Unable to click ON or OFF button of Tail Mode again in server log page of Runtime - Monitor - Log Files HAL-1549 Encoding issue in French localization HAL-1546 Obtain certificate button of key-store runtime view should use a new alias HAL-1545 Enhance the SSL Wizard to add support to LetsEncrypt CA HAL-1543 Display microprofile health checks on HAL HAL-1540 Not possible to configure Microprofile Config subsystem to obtain ConfigSource from a directory HAL-1539 NPE when insert a panel item in VerticalNavigation when there a second level items HAL-1537 Support Eclipse MicroProfile Metrics in Web Console HAL-1528 Add support to several messaging-activemq resources HAL-1526 Required field error when rolling back a patch HAL-1523 Add support for server-ssl-sni-context added to WildFly Elytron subsystem HAL-1521 Add support for JASPI as added to the WildFly Elytron Subsystem HAL-1520 ModelBrowser form doesn&amp;rsquo;t show values if they are expressions and read-only HAL-1519 Undeploy operation wording is not unified HAL-1517 Composite operation needs settable address HAL-1515 The &amp;ldquo;name&amp;rdquo; field of &amp;ldquo;Add&amp;rdquo; dialog for JCA distributed work manager is read only HAL-1514 Add messaging server requires the path=* subresources if a server already exists HAL-1513 Enable deployments by default HAL-1512 Support Wildfly in EMBEDDED mode HAL-1511 Cross-site scripting (XSS) in JBoss Management Console HAL-1510 Add &amp;ldquo;init&amp;rdquo; runtime operation to trust-manager HAL-1509 Creating a non-local cache container in web console fails HAL-1508 Check and update links used in the &amp;lsquo;Need Help&amp;rsquo; section of the homepage HAL-1507 Show logs from logging-profile in log viewer HAL-1505 Requests for pollyfill.</description></item><item><title>3.2.0.Final</title><link>https://hal.github.io/releases/3.2.0.final/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 14:29:15 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://hal.github.io/releases/3.2.0.final/</guid><description>Target: WildFly 17.0.0.Final Tag: 3.2.0.Final Tracking Issue: WFLY-12001 New Features HAL-1578 Add support for custom title HAL-1576 Add BusyWorkerThreadCount metric in IO WorkerPreview HAL-1399 Specify port for standalone mode Bugfixes HAL-1398 Empty error message when connecting w/o user HAL-1568 Add support for error and unauthorized places using the GWTP way HAL-1569 Missing reset link on forms of elytron resources HAL-1570 Do not automatically set datasource-class at datasource wizard https://issues.</description></item><item><title>3.2.1.Final</title><link>https://hal.github.io/releases/3.2.1.final/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 12:19:12 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://hal.github.io/releases/3.2.1.final/</guid><description> Target: WildFly 18.0.1.Final Tag: 3.2.1.Final Tracking Issue: 12399 New Features HAL-1618: Support changed lifecycle hosts / servers HAL-1613: Improve tag handling HAL-1609: Configure new / enhanced password mappers HAL-1607: Configure HotRod session manager in distributable-web subsystem HAL-1601: Expose named-formatter attribute for syslog-handler HAL-1562: Upgrade jboss-parent to 35 HAL-1414: Show as CLI command for configuration changes Bugfixes HAL-1627: Fix store and memory element HAL-1588: Added filtering for server urls only to bound ones HAL-1581: JMS in domain mode reports error</description></item><item><title>3.2.4.Final</title><link>https://hal.github.io/releases/3.2.4.final/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 17:18:12 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://hal.github.io/releases/3.2.4.final/</guid><description> Target: JBoss EAP 7.3.0 Tag: 3.2.4.Final Tracking Issue: JBEAP-17949 Bugfixes JBEAP-18050: Error when maintaining Datasources &amp;amp; Drivers via Console JBEAP-17920: Console does not display destination list, if the messaging server name is in caps JBEAP-17892: RBAC: Deployment button not available for server group scoped role</description></item><item><title>3.2.7.Final</title><link>https://hal.github.io/releases/3.2.7.final/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 17:18:12 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://hal.github.io/releases/3.2.7.final/</guid><description>Target: WildFly 19.0.0.Final Tag: 3.2.7.Final Tracking Issue: WFLY-13143 Bugfixes HAL-1668: Close blocking dialog after errors HAL-1667: Encode resource address values when used to create an address template HAL-1663: Add null saftey check during life cycle operations HAL-1662: Adjust finder path when servers have been stopped HAL-1660: Fix browseByHosts() / browseByServerGroups() FinderContext.getPath() might be reversed after coming back from an application HAL-1659: Driver-XA-datasource class for mysql is poiniting to incorrect class HAL-1658: Fix address handling in composite operation HAL-1657: Change metadata address templates for host related classes (partly undoes HAL-1640) HAL-1655: Mysql driver class is pointing to wrong path on admin console while creating - datasource HAL-1653: Fix wrong composite failure construction in timeout handler HAL-1649: HAL Management Console black screen - Syntax Error in polyfill.</description></item><item><title>3.3.1.Final</title><link>https://hal.github.io/releases/3.3.1.final/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 10:18:12 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://hal.github.io/releases/3.3.1.final/</guid><description>Target: WildFly 23.0.0.Final Tag: 3.3.1.Final Tracking Issue: WFLY-14429 Bugfixes HAL-636: Enhancing the bootstrap server setup process HAL-1629: Displaying loading panel during the replace of deployment HAL-1633: Enable JAXRS subsystem HAL-1638: Add &amp;lsquo;*&amp;rsquo; as allowed character for properties item HAL-1658: Fix address resolution HAL-1669: Add object attribute support to model browser HAL-1670: Added parentheses to allowed chars for properties HAL-1671: When using admin console to create xa-datasource &amp;ldquo;_&amp;rdquo; is not allowed in xa datasource properties HAL-1673: ClassNotFoundException thrown while creating DB2 datasource from Management console using default driver class HAL-1677: Fix for possible undefined host element for host-scoped-role HAL-1678: IBM DB2 datasource creation via console is pointing to incorrect xa- datasource class HAL-1679: No need to replace wildcard for {selected.</description></item><item><title>3.3.7.Final</title><link>https://hal.github.io/releases/3.3.7.final/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 09:24:23 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://hal.github.io/releases/3.3.7.final/</guid><description>Target: WildFly 24.0.0.Final Tag: 3.3.7.Final Tracking Issue: WFLY-14891 Bugfixes HAL-1556: Consolidate names and i18n resources HAL-1722: Only latest applied patch can be rolled back HAL-1729: Add IDs for tests HAL-1736: Fix mixing session creation and last access time HAL-1738: Replace deprecated attribute HAL-1740: Fix security handling in Model Browser HAL-1742: Fix address parsing when address contains duplicate parts HAL-1745: Make autosuggestions HTML safe HAL-1747: Request place builder should check selected server rather than - selected profile for runtime undertow deployment HAL-1748: messaging runtime server column should build with selected server.</description></item><item><title>3.4.1.Final</title><link>https://hal.github.io/releases/3.4.1.final/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 08:12:23 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://hal.github.io/releases/3.4.1.final/</guid><description> Target: WildFly 26.0.0.Final Tag: 3.4.1.Final Tracking Issue: WFLY-15766 New Features HAL-1737: Add content hash to deployment preview HAL-1729: Show non-heap-memory-usage in server preview HAL-1710: Fix update of credential reference HAL-1645: Manage constants headers HAL-1625: Add pause/resume actions to JMS Topic HAL-1597: Configure session affinity using multiple routes if supported by balancer HAL-1580: Implement a form item for simple lists of objects Bugfixes HAL-1762: Aliases are removed from the credential store when passwords are updated from the admin console HAL-1761: Fix data source creation wizard w/ test connection and cred-ref HAL-1760: Editing credential reference is not working HAL-1759: Update EAP8 version in i18n constants properties</description></item><item><title>Custom Title</title><link>https://hal.github.io/blog/custom-title/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 10:30:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://hal.github.io/blog/custom-title/</guid><description>HAL 3.2.0 which is part of Wildfly 17 comes with a new option to customize the title of the browser window / tab. This is especially useful if you have multiple HAL windows open and need to know which console manages which WildFly instance.
The new features makes use of two attributes in the root resource of the management model:
name: The name of this server. If not set, defaults to the runtime value of InetAddress.</description></item><item><title>What is new in HAL 3.1.2</title><link>https://hal.github.io/blog/whats-new-hal-312/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 08:30:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://hal.github.io/blog/whats-new-hal-312/</guid><description>HAL 3.1.2 is released and packaged as part of Wildfly 16 (which is in Candidate Release as of now and soon will release a Final).
HAL 3.1.2 brings many new features, bug fixes and enhancements, checkout the release notes since HAL 3.0.6, which is the version packaged in Wildfly 14 and 15.
The new and noteworthy features are:
Support socket log handler Show logs from logging-profile in log viewer Display microprofile health checks Expose CA management operations for key-store and certificate-authority-account Enhance the SSL Wizard to add support to LetsEncrypt CA Support runtime operations for messaging servers Add support to remote ActiveMQ server Display the the network open ports Show active management operation from hosts and servers in a central place Show unresponsive controller better Basic support to MicroProfile Metrics and Config If you find any problem, bug or have a suggestion on how to improve HAL, please open an issue or contact us.</description></item><item><title>Monitor active management operations and detect non-progressing operations</title><link>https://hal.github.io/blog/management-operations/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 08:30:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://hal.github.io/blog/management-operations/</guid><description>A management operation is when any api client that connects to the Wildfly kernel and run operations to read from a running server or write a configuration. Examples of a management operation:
Add a datasource. Deploy an application. Change the undertow buffer pool. A domain controller updates a slave server configuration. Host/Server synchronization. The following tasks are not management operations:
A HTTP request from a browser to a deployed application.</description></item><item><title>Inspect HTTP Sessions</title><link>https://hal.github.io/blog/inspect-http-sessions/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 14:03:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://hal.github.io/blog/inspect-http-sessions/</guid><description>The undertow subsystem in deployments has been enhanced and provides new operations to inspect HTTP sessions.
Session Statistics To see session statistics please select a deployment under &amp;ldquo;Runtime / Server / Web / Deployment&amp;rdquo;. Besides the main attributes like deployment name and context path, the preview shows statistics for the number of active, expired and invalid sessions. Besides that you can see statistics about the session time.
Session Attributes If you select a deployment and press &amp;ldquo;View&amp;rdquo;, you can see more details about the deployment.</description></item><item><title>Log all configuration changes</title><link>https://hal.github.io/blog/configuration-changes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 15:30:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://hal.github.io/blog/configuration-changes/</guid><description>There is a feature to record all configuration changes to an in-memory log per host or server, it records any change performed on Wildfly, for example: deploy an application, add a datasource, change any configuration, add any resource. This blog post will show how it works.
Notes:
For this blog post, domain mode will be used. After a domain or server restart all configuration changes are lost, because this is an in-memory logging.</description></item><item><title>Protect Wildfly HTTP Management Interface with SSL</title><link>https://hal.github.io/blog/protect-mgmt-interface-ssl/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 15:30:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://hal.github.io/blog/protect-mgmt-interface-ssl/</guid><description>In WildFly 13, there is a wizard to enable the SSL for the HTTP management interface, it uses the elytron resource to manage the security features. The certificate may be handled in the following ways:
Generate a self-signed certificate Use an existing certificate file Use an existing elytron key-store Use mutual authentication with a client You can see more information about elytron features and HTTPS in general.
The wizard may create the following resources to add SSL to the HTTP Management Interface:</description></item><item><title>New Infinispan Resources</title><link>https://hal.github.io/blog/new-infinispan-resources/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 15:30:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://hal.github.io/blog/new-infinispan-resources/</guid><description>In WildFly 13 the Infinispan subsystem introduces several new resources:
Remote Cache Container Scattered Cache Hot Rod Store All of these resources are supported in the latest HAL version (3.0.3 and above).
Remote Cache Container Remote cache containers are listed together with regular cache containers in the &amp;lsquo;Cache Container&amp;rsquo; column. You can use the button drop down to add both remote and regular cache containers.
Scattered Cache All caches of the selected cache container are now displayed in their own column.</description></item></channel></rss>