<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Recent Posts on HAL Management Console</title><link>https://hal.github.io/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Recent Posts on HAL Management Console</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 16:00:23 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hal.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Custom Title</title><link>https://hal.github.io/blog/custom-title/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 10:30:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://hal.github.io/blog/custom-title/</guid><description>HAL 3.2.0 which is part of Wildfly 17 comes with a new option to customize the title of the browser window / tab. This is especially useful if you have multiple HAL windows open and need to know which console manages which WildFly instance.
The new features makes use of two attributes in the root resource of the management model:
name: The name of this server. If not set, defaults to the runtime value of InetAddress.</description></item><item><title>What is new in HAL 3.1.2</title><link>https://hal.github.io/blog/whats-new-hal-312/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 08:30:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://hal.github.io/blog/whats-new-hal-312/</guid><description>HAL 3.1.2 is released and packaged as part of Wildfly 16 (which is in Candidate Release as of now and soon will release a Final).
HAL 3.1.2 brings many new features, bug fixes and enhancements, checkout the release notes since HAL 3.0.6, which is the version packaged in Wildfly 14 and 15.
The new and noteworthy features are:
Support socket log handler Show logs from logging-profile in log viewer Display microprofile health checks Expose CA management operations for key-store and certificate-authority-account Enhance the SSL Wizard to add support to LetsEncrypt CA Support runtime operations for messaging servers Add support to remote ActiveMQ server Display the the network open ports Show active management operation from hosts and servers in a central place Show unresponsive controller better Basic support to MicroProfile Metrics and Config If you find any problem, bug or have a suggestion on how to improve HAL, please open an issue or contact us.</description></item><item><title>Monitor active management operations and detect non-progressing operations</title><link>https://hal.github.io/blog/management-operations/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 08:30:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://hal.github.io/blog/management-operations/</guid><description>A management operation is when any api client that connects to the Wildfly kernel and run operations to read from a running server or write a configuration. Examples of a management operation:
Add a datasource. Deploy an application. Change the undertow buffer pool. A domain controller updates a slave server configuration. Host/Server synchronization. The following tasks are not management operations:
A HTTP request from a browser to a deployed application.</description></item><item><title>Inspect HTTP Sessions</title><link>https://hal.github.io/blog/inspect-http-sessions/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 14:03:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://hal.github.io/blog/inspect-http-sessions/</guid><description>The undertow subsystem in deployments has been enhanced and provides new operations to inspect HTTP sessions.
Session Statistics To see session statistics please select a deployment under &amp;ldquo;Runtime / Server / Web / Deployment&amp;rdquo;. Besides the main attributes like deployment name and context path, the preview shows statistics for the number of active, expired and invalid sessions. Besides that you can see statistics about the session time.
Session Attributes If you select a deployment and press &amp;ldquo;View&amp;rdquo;, you can see more details about the deployment.</description></item><item><title>Log all configuration changes</title><link>https://hal.github.io/blog/configuration-changes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 15:30:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://hal.github.io/blog/configuration-changes/</guid><description>There is a feature to record all configuration changes to an in-memory log per host or server, it records any change performed on Wildfly, for example: deploy an application, add a datasource, change any configuration, add any resource. This blog post will show how it works.
Notes:
For this blog post, domain mode will be used. After a domain or server restart all configuration changes are lost, because this is an in-memory logging.</description></item><item><title>Protect Wildfly HTTP Management Interface with SSL</title><link>https://hal.github.io/blog/protect-mgmt-interface-ssl/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 15:30:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://hal.github.io/blog/protect-mgmt-interface-ssl/</guid><description>In WildFly 13, there is a wizard to enable the SSL for the HTTP management interface, it uses the elytron resource to manage the security features. The certificate may be handled in the following ways:
Generate a self-signed certificate Use an existing certificate file Use an existing elytron key-store Use mutual authentication with a client You can see more information about elytron features and HTTPS in general.
The wizard may create the following resources to add SSL to the HTTP Management Interface:</description></item><item><title>New Infinispan Resources</title><link>https://hal.github.io/blog/new-infinispan-resources/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 15:30:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://hal.github.io/blog/new-infinispan-resources/</guid><description>In WildFly 13 the Infinispan subsystem introduces several new resources:
Remote Cache Container Scattered Cache Hot Rod Store All of these resources are supported in the latest HAL version (3.0.3 and above).
Remote Cache Container Remote cache containers are listed together with regular cache containers in the &amp;lsquo;Cache Container&amp;rsquo; column. You can use the button drop down to add both remote and regular cache containers.
Scattered Cache All caches of the selected cache container are now displayed in their own column.</description></item></channel></rss>