<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Documentation on HAL Management Console</title><link>https://hal.github.io/documentation/</link><description>Recent content in Documentation on HAL Management Console</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 07:54:34 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hal.github.io/documentation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Get Started</title><link>https://hal.github.io/documentation/get-started/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 16:28:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://hal.github.io/documentation/get-started/</guid><description>The HAL management console is part of every WildFly and JBoss EAP installation. To get started simply fire up your browser and open http://localhost:9990.
Standalone Mode Besides that you can run the console on its own aka standalone mode. HAL is a RIA with no server side dependencies. When run on its own, HAL will show a dialog when it&amp;rsquo;s started. You have to provide the URL of the management endpoint you want to connect to.</description></item><item><title>Basic Concepts</title><link>https://hal.github.io/documentation/concepts/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 16:29:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://hal.github.io/documentation/concepts/</guid><description>HAL uses a set of UI components which follow the design guides from PatternFly. If necessary, these UI components are extended and adapted to the needs of HAL. The following chapters explain the most important concepts and their use.
Header &amp;amp; Footer The header and footer provide access to global features and give feedback about various states of WildFly. The color of the top line in the header shows the used theme:</description></item><item><title>Manual</title><link>https://hal.github.io/documentation/manual/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 16:29:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://hal.github.io/documentation/manual/</guid><description>The HAL management console features a rich user interface to configure, analyse and monitor the complete WildFly management model. The console uses six top level categories: homepage, deployments, configuration, runtime, patching and access control. In addition HAL uses a header and footer to provide access to global features and give feedback about various states of WildFly and HAL.
This page gives a quick introduction to the main elements in the header and footer and the six top level categories.</description></item><item><title>Recipes &amp; How To</title><link>https://hal.github.io/documentation/howto/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 11:14:45 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://hal.github.io/documentation/howto/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Contribute</title><link>https://hal.github.io/documentation/contribute/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 16:30:37 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://hal.github.io/documentation/contribute/</guid><description>First off, thank you for considering contributing to HAL. It&amp;rsquo;s people like you that make HAL such a great tool. HAL is an open source project and we love to receive contributions from our community — you! There are many ways to contribute, from writing tutorials or blog posts, improving the documentation, submitting bug reports and feature requests or writing code which can be incorporated into HAL itself.
Getting involved is easier than you think.</description></item><item><title>Roadmap</title><link>https://hal.github.io/documentation/roadmap/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 11:24:57 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://hal.github.io/documentation/roadmap/</guid><description>HAL is community-driven and as such the roadmap constantly evolves to reflect the users needs and contributions. You can find a list of planned issues and feature requests in our issue tracker, but this page is a good starting point to see where we are going.
Short-Term For the next releases we want to expose new features added to the various subsystems. This is an excerpt of issues we&amp;rsquo;re currently working on:</description></item></channel></rss>